ASHISH TIWARI

A-69 Delhi Citizen Society Sector 13 Rohini New Delhi 110085 - ashish.epost@gmail.com - +91-9999394107

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer having Angular with LAMP Proficiency with hands-on experience of Hybrid Mobile Application development with Ionic3. Fully Snugged with AWS Services like EC2, RDS, S3, Billing, Backup, etc. Comfortable with Applium Testing Automation, Web-Scraping, Shell Scripting, Web & Windows Automation.

SKILLS

Front-End : Angular, AngularJS, JavaScript, Html/Html5, Css/Css3, Bootstrap

Back-End: Php, MySql, Apache2, TomcatCloud Platforms: AWS Services-: EC2, RDS, S3 & SNSOperating Systems: Windows, Linux, macOS, Android, iOS

CMS/FSS: Joomla, PrestaShop, Pydio

Graphics Editor : Photoshop

Automation: Python, Selenium, Appium, Autoit, Imacros

Version-Control System : Git, Github

WORK EXPERIENCE

Incedo Inc. (Senior Software Engineer, 08.2016 – Present) [2.4 Years]

Successfully deployed all assigned projects & POC's

- Developed & Deployed cFAx Project using Angular 5.0
- Developed Hybrid Mobile Application for cFax project Ionic 3.0
- Complete Angular Code Review for Belden Project
- Successfully Conducted Internal Trainings on Angular 5.0
- Worked on various POC's
- Managing Team of 3
- Finalize UI Designs
- Maintaining AWS Instances
- Conducting L2 Round Interview
- Setup & Maintaining Linux Machine on Intranet
- Maintaining MySQL Database on RDS
- Design & Development of REST API's using CodeIgnitor

IARI Pusa Institute (Research Associate, 06.2013 – 08.2016) [3.2 Years]

Worked for Government Internal Project related to Maps for backend & frontend

- Worked on responsive Geoportal Web Interface using JavaScript libraries Openlayers, GeoExt & framework AngularJS, JavaScript & Phonegap/Cordova.
- Huge Satellite Data acquisition & parsing is done of JSON Format.
- Geoserver is used at the server side to render & publish requested maps. URL: http://geoportal.icar.gov.in/
- Completely developed responsive Meteorological Web Charts using Highchart & JQuery Library, which show various parameters like Maximum & Minimum Temperature, Relative Humidity

- Morning Evening, etc. For server side PHP code is written to query MySQL database to respond the data in JSON objects.
- Automated Reporting application is developed for generating PDF reports automatically every week by querying MySQL database using DebenuTM Commercial SDK & AutoIT Automation API
- Centos Linux based CRON jobs are created to backup automatically MySQL databases in every two weeks
- Maintaining Linux based Centos system as supplied by Seascape USA
- For data acquisition, processing & Visualization from various satellites like NOAA satellite
- Web Automations are created using iMacros Automation & JavaScript

Creative Web Mania (Software Engineer, 05.2012 – 05.2013) [1.2 Years]

Worked on Third-Party clients of company for designing & developing Webapps using CMS & web technologies & hosting maintenance

- Control Linux based Web Hosting panels like cPanel/WHM
- Complete website designed using Joomla 3.0
- Integrated Custom Code by designing Joomla Plugins
- Template Customizations for various templates
- Complete Online Shopping cart is created using PrestaShop shopping cart Platform
- Using Open-Source Technologies & Maintaining Godaddy Hosting Account
- Some Projects using various CMS
 - o anagharecruitments.com
 - service.sdentalart.com
 - o antmedicals.com

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application (MCA) [U.P.T.U – 61.8%] **Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)** [G.N.D.U – 59.8%]

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Programmed Atmel 80C51 Series Embedded Devices.
- Automating Ajax & Non-Ajax based Websites like Justdial, bigbasket, Indiamart, Olympiadhelper.com etc. for Web Scraping using Python, Selenium & iMacros.
- Automate Windows for almost any GUI Activities using COM objects
- PDF & DOCX formats Automation using Python Automation
- Working on Project olympiadbox.com Completely Designed API Structure, Front-End, Database, Integration Mechanism.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 6th November 1986 **Languages** : English, Hindi

Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indian
Passport Number : (K1805319)

Awards : Incedo Inc.: MAD, ICE